本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译   米小勒    Lottie筱妤   小欠    Marshal同学   蔡茸茸
翻译   CS小明漫画家   天启章鱼X   kiko   我叫魏碧慧   迷失_绽放
时间轴   太太乐叽叽  SumenQ     后期   蜡笔小新的眉毛
校对   米小勒      总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on "Z Nation".
我就是不相信摩菲好吗
I just don't trust Murphy, okay?
那家伙肯定有古怪
There's something wrong with that dude.
万一这是真的呢
What if it's true?
万一摩菲真如他们所说的那样
What if Murphy's who they say he is
万一我们真有机会制造出疫苗呢
and there's a chance for a vaccine?
不可能的
It's not.
那是个谎话  而且这谎话会害死我们的
It's a lie, and it's gonna get us both killed.
那我也情愿因相信这个谎话而死
Well then I'd rather die believing in a lie
总好过没有信仰地苟且活着
than live believing in nothing.
为什么会有人把你关在笼子里不管你死活
Why would somebody lock you in a cage and leave you to die?
我用不着为自己辩白
I don't have to justify myself.
也许你需要
Maybe you do!
要是我告诉他们你是谁的话会怎么样
What happens when I tell them what you are?
懦夫
Coward!
上达比  宾夕法尼亚州
所以...
So...
到底是什么风把你吹来费城了  宝贝
What brings you to Philly, baby?
想来做点小买卖而已
Looking to do a little bartering.
你的名字真叫"阳光"吗
Your name really Sunshine?
有关系吗
Does it mater?
我想没有
I guess not.
我已经很久
It has been a long time
没见过女人的胴体了
since I saw a woman's body.
至少是个鲜活的女人
At least a living woman.
你在颤抖
You're shaking.
没事的  宝贝  只不过有点冷
It's nothing, baby. Just the cold.
那看看我们能否帮你暖和起来
Well let's see if we can warm you up.
你是不是忘了该拿出点什么  亲爱的
Are you forgetting something, lover?
好的
Right.
这玩意我还能搞来更多呢
And there's plenty more where that came from.
我们开做吧
Let's do this.
臭婊子
Crazy bitch!
你想偷我东西是吧
You trying to rip me off?
让我来教育教育你
I'll teach you.
我好像告诉了你不准有暴力行为
Thought I told you no rough stuff?
那是你找错了人
You picked the wrong mark.
有些人就是不听话
Some people just don't listen.
快去搜他的外套
Go check his jacket.
看来有人可以去嗨趴体喽
Somebody likes to party.
给我
Give me that.
去查查看他有没有武器
Make sure he doesn't have any weapons.
你怎么搞的
And what happened to you?
你忘了我怎么教你的了吗
You forget everything I taught you?
我试着按你教我的来对付他
I tried to do it exactly like you showed me,
可是他太壮了
but he was too strong.
我下次会努力地  我保证
I'll do it better next time. I promise.
你不能畏首畏尾
You can't be afraid.
片刻的犹豫会让你死无葬身之地
Hesitation will get you killed.
你知道我爱你  阳光
You know I love you, Sunshine.
就像我爱我所有的孩子们一样
Like I love all my children.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
为何我们要走这条路  费城是个死城了
Why are we going this way? Philly's a dead zone.
但愿我们能在不过于深入城市的情况下
Hopefully we can scavenge something
找到点有用的东西
without going too deep into the city.
如果我们能找到好用的无线电
If we find a working radio,
我们就能试着去联系那个Z家伙
we can try to contact that Z guy again.
费城
Philadelphia.
充满手足之情的都市
Ah, the city of brotherly love.
那不会是我认为的那东西吧
Is that what I think it is?
不可能
No way.
费城独立厅的大钟  1776年7月4日鸣钟宣布美国独立
那真的是独立钟吗
Is that really the Liberty Bell?
"在此宣告所有土地
"Proclaim liberty throughout all
以及所有的公民获得自由"
the land and unto all the inhabitants thereof."
是啊  是它
Yeah, that's it.
僵尸大灾变三年以来
Three years of zombie apocalypse,
你以为自己什么都见过了
you think you've seen everything.
当实事每况愈下时
Well when everything went bad,
可能有人还想拯救一些历史文物
they probably tried to save a little history.
话是没错  不过这些人应该知道
Yeah, well they should've known
乱世中  你能拯救的只有自己
the only thing you can save is yourself.
我们走吧
Let's go!
等等
Hang on.
如果这辆车还有汽油  果然有
If this thing still has fuel, and it does...
如果我们开始这样做
If we get this thing started,
他们就不必毫无保护地坐在露天车后斗了
they won't have to ride out in the open like that.
我完全赞成
Well I'm all for that.
我去拿跨接电缆
I'll grab the jumper cable.
上帝保佑全人类
God bless the human race.
百分之九十九都阵亡了
99% of them dead.
但还有一个拿着喷雾罐的混蛋活着
But there's still one jackass alive with a spray can.
一千零七十五
One thousand seventy-five.
好了  发动试试
Okay, give it a shot.
没问题  我们走吧  摩菲
All right, that's it. Let's go, Murphy.
你进去跟我和沃伦一起坐
You get in here with Warren and me.
其他人  坐进我们捡来的那辆车
Everybody else, follow in the pickup.
跟紧了
Stay close.
你不必把僵尸赶尽杀绝  留几个活口
You know you could try to miss some of them instead.
为什么  杀一个少一个
Why? One less zombie to kill.
给那个叫两千的神经病小伙留几个
Leave some for Psycho-Boy Two Thousand.
-人家叫一万  -一万
- Ten Thousand. - Ten Thousand.
一万吗
Ten Thousand?
看来现在的年轻人还有点追求  不错
It's good to know kids today still have some goals.
我们不是真的要一路护送那个叫摩菲的人
We're not really going all the way to California
去加利福尼亚吧
with this Murphy guy, are we?
我们计划这样去做
That's the plan.
这太疯狂了
That's crazy.
他到底有什么与众不同的地方
What's so special about him anyway?
他的血液
His blood.
你悠着点  你就剩那么点水了
Hey, take it easy there. That's the last of your water.
其实  那是她的水
Actually it's the last of her water.
我的水在这里
Mine's right here.
给我
Give me that.
虽然我们要把你活着送到加利福尼亚去
Just because we got to get you to California alive
但我在路上依然可以揍你
doesn't mean I can't kick your ass between here and there.
当心
Look out!
上帝啊
God!
太爽了  我愿意花钱再看一遍
Yeah! I'd pay money to see that again.
车的轴承坏了
The axel's broke.
好了  大家都上那辆车
All right, everybody get into that truck.
我们走  摩菲  走吧
Let's go, Murphy. Come on.
下车  我来开
Get out. I'm driving.
北极光
美国国安局作战指挥中心
看上去还不错吧  小狗
Lookin' good, eh pup?
两块二十盎司的T骨牛扒  陈年佳肴
Two twenty ounce T-bone steaks aged to perfection.
你说什么
What's that?
你那块要三成熟吗
You like yours rare?
我也是哦  咱俩在这点上达成一致了
Well me too. We've got that in common.
存放这些牛排的地方还有很多存货
Oh and there's plenty more where this came from.
确切的说  还有半吨
Half a ton to be exact.
不只是T骨牛扒哦
And that's just the T-bones.
我们还有纽约牛排  牛腰肉
We got New York strips, sirloins,
甚至还有菲列牛排
and even some filet mignon.
这些牛排和即食餐是供给
Between that and MREs to feed
一个军队半年的口粮
a division for six months
我敢说  只有咱俩在僵尸大灾变时期
I'd say you and I are gonna be the only two getting fat
长胖了
for the apocalypse.
上菜了
Here you go.
请慢慢享用这块牛排
Enjoy that beef.
多少人会为了这样的牛排不惜大肆杀戮
There are people out there that'd kill for that steak.
外面可是弱肉强食[狗咬狗]的世界哦
It's a dog eat dog world out there, man.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
用词不当  应该是人肉尸食的世界
Wrong word choice. It's more of a zombie eat man world.
在一起享用我们的劳动成果之前
As we share in the fruit of our labor,
有一点我们必须牢记在心
let it remind us now more than ever,
我们要互相依靠
that we need each other.
我们需要家庭
We need family.
虽然我带领大家挺过了黑色夏季
As I led us through Black Summer,
但大家都曾动摇过
you all had doubts.
连我也动摇过
Even I did.
但我们作为一家人团结在一起
But we pulled together as a family
艰苦奋斗生存下去
and did what we had to do.
千百万人像野兽那样饿死在街头
Millions died starving in the streets like animals.
但我们挺住了  我们作为一个大家庭挺住了
But we survived. We survived as a family.
我们美丽的母亲为我们指明了道路
Our beautiful mother showed us the way.
教会了我们如何成为一家人
Taught us what it meant to be a family.
但我心中还是有缺憾
But there is a hole in my heart.
我们这个家庭还有缺憾
A hole in this family.
我们的"阳光"不见了
Our Sunshine is missing.
只要她不在我们中间  这个家就不完整
And until she returns to us our family's not complete.
这个保卫大家的集体就有了缺口
The circle that keeps us safe is broken.
阿门
Amen.
太好了
Excellent.
你可以多吃一份  干得漂亮
Get yourself an extra serving. You did good.
各位  好消息来了
Good news, everyone.
阳光已经找到了  我们的集体不再有缺憾
Sunshine has been found. The circle will not be broken.
好好享受吧  这是最后的干粮了
Enjoy. That's the last of the food.
我的天  饿得我肚子里大肠吃小肠
God, I'm so hungry my big guts are eating my little guts.
你吃不下了吗
You gonna eat all of that?
自私的小混蛋
Selfish little bastard.
我们必须分头寻找食物和水
We need to split up and look for food and water.
对了  如果能找到双向无线电
Oh, if we can find a two way radio or
哪怕是卫星天线盘都行
even like a satellite dish,
我就能试着联系那个市民Z
I can try and contact that Citizen Z guy.
非常好  你和麦克去找这个
That's good. Okay, you and Mack do that.
剩下的人去找补给
And the rest of us will look for food.
多克  你  卡桑德拉还有一万是一队
Doc, you take Cassandra and 10K.
沃伦  我和摩菲是一队  大家别走散了
Warren and I will take Murphy. Stay close.
一小时后在这会合
Meet back here in an hour.
好  出发
All right, let's go.
宾夕法尼亚州  费城
那里的无线电能用
I want that radio.
行  僵尸警长怎么办
Yeah, what about Officer Zombie?
你还记得皮克斯基尔那次吗
Do you remember that time in Peekskill?
那招挺好  你在上还是我在上
Yeah, that's perfect. Top or bottom?
我吧
Top.
你  就是你
Hey, you. Yeah.
漂亮
Oh, baby.
我要是哪天需要人"施以仁慈"
You know if I ever need mercy,
我真心希望你来动手
I really hope it's you.
来  我要看看这无线电还能不能用
Come on. I want to see if that radio works.
好  快点  我去捅几个当地市民去
All right, hurry up. I'll pike some locals.
我勒个去
Jesus Christ.
好吧
Okay.
小子
Hey, kid.
能不能上来帮个忙
Give me a hand with this, will ya?
我不明白为什么非要在费城停留
I don't know why we stopped here in Philly.
我们应该继续往前走
We should've kept going.
走哪去
Going where?
我们需要跟那个市民哥们联系上
We need to find a way to communicate with that Citizen dude.
我觉得这个天线盘艾迪用得上
And I think Addy can do something with this dish.
谁知道 没准运气好还能收着毛片频道呢
Who knows, maybe we'll get lucky and pick up porn.
从没看过毛片
Never seen porn.
你从没看过毛片吗
You never seen porn?
不会吧  从来没看过吗
Really? Never?
我还没到年龄嘛
Before my time.
好看吗
Is it good?
-当然好看  -还行吧
- Yeah. - Meh.
阳光
Sunshine!
我居然被自己恶心到了
That even disgusted me.
因为只有我自己在这里恶心
'Course I'm the only one here to disgust.
除了你
Except for you.
可是你只是条狗  你才不在乎
But you're a dog. What do you care?
对不起
Sorry.
我的阳光去哪里了
Where's my Sunshine?
那婊子居然从我手中溜走了
Bitch gave me the slip.
你在说的是你妹妹
That's your sister you're talking about.
我们很快就会找到她
We'll find her soon enough.
同时  有块肥肉送上门来了
Meanwhile, another opportunity has presented itself.
求救  求救
Mayday. Mayday.
呼叫任何能接收此频率的人
Calling anybody on this frequency.
信号输入
接收到一个发自费城的射频信号
Picking up some kind of RF signal out of Philadelphia.
好像是警察用的信号
Looks like something on the police band.
求救  求救  我是三角洲X光小队的
Mayday. Mayday. This is Addison Carver
艾迪生·卡弗
with Delta-Xray-Delta.
尝试联系市民Z  请回复  市民Z
Trying to contact Citizen Z. Come in, Citizen Z.
求救  求救
Mayday. Mayday.
三角洲X光小队  我是市民Z
Delta-Xray-Delta, this is Citizen Z.
听到吗  完毕
Do you copy? Over.
我听得非常清楚  听到我说话吗
I'm picking you up loud and clear. Do you copy me?
听得非常清楚  市民Z
Copy you loud and clear Citizen Z.
三角洲X光小队  请回复
Delta-Xray-Delta, come in.
三角洲X光小队  请汇报情况
Delta-Xray-Delta, what is your status?
三角洲X光小队
Delta-Xray-Delta.
请汇报情况
What is your status?
三角洲X光小队
Delta-Xray.
有人吗  你没事吧
Anybody. Are you all right?
请汇报情况  三角洲X光小队
What is your status, Delta-Xray?
三角洲X光小队  请回复
Delta-Xray, please respond.
三角洲X光小队  听到吗
Delta-Xray, do you copy.
那里发生什么事了
Hey, what's going on down there?
包裹还安全吗
Is the package safe?
重复  包裹还安全吗  听到吗
Repeat, is the package safe? Do you copy?
请回复
Please respond.
如果你还活着  请回复
If you're alive, please respond.
艾迪  艾迪·卡弗  听到吗
Addy? Addy Carver, do you copy?
好吧
All right.
那就试着用老方法
Let's go old school here
看看能否用三角定位出信号来源
and see if we can triangulate where that signal came from.
哪些小伙伴们还在费城活跃呢
What assets are hot in Philadelphia?
信号频率好像是...警察用的
Signal frequency looks like... the police band.
费城不可能还会有警察活着的
There can't be any cops left in Philly.
那里在两年前就已经是死城了
It's been a dead zone for like two years.
也许他们开启了警察的对讲机
Maybe they hot-wired a cop's walkie.
我想念爱德华·斯诺登和僵尸出现前的日子了
I miss the ol' days before Edward Snowden... and zombies.
那时我们多了不起
We were such badasses.
艾迪  好使吗  艾迪  艾迪
Addy, did it work? Addy? Addy!
艾迪  你在哪里
Addy! Where are you?
天啊  宝贝  不不不不不
Oh Jesus, baby. Baby, no, no, no, no, no!
艾迪
Addy.
你不是艾迪
You're not Addy.
她在哪里
Where is she?
艾迪
Addy!
三角洲X光小队
Delta-Xray-Delta.
三角洲X光小队  请回复
Delta-Xray-Delta, come in.
在在在在
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我们在这  我们在这
We're here. We're here.
三角洲X什么的  我们听到
Delta-X whatever, we copy.
明白  三角洲X光小队
Gotcha, Delta-Xray.
请问说话的是谁
Who am I speaking to?
马克·汤姆森  但这不是重点
Mack Thompson, but that doesn't matter right now.
刚才有个女人在这  你和她通话了吗
There was a woman here. Did you talk to her?
收到
Roger that.
我刚才跟一位名叫  艾迪的人通话了
I made contact with someone named... Addy?
是的  艾迪  艾迪  你刚才和她通话了
Yeah, Addy! Addy, yeah. Yeah, you talked to her, okay.
她怎么样了
Is she okay?
她有没有  有没有告诉你她要去哪
Did she... did she tell you where she was going?
不清楚她的位置
Negative on her location.
我们只说了几句话
We only talked for like a second.
好像发生了什么事
Something happened.
该死的僵尸们
Goddamn Zs.
也许不是僵尸
Maybe not.
我听到了声音  人类的声音
I heard voices. Human voices.
还有挣扎的声音
And then some sort of struggle.
人类吗
Humans?
是这样的
Roger that.
该死的人类吗
Goddamn humans?
包裹怎么样了
What about the package?
什么包裹
What package?
莫菲  零号病患
Murphy. Patient Zero.
咬痕研究所  他还活着吗
Operation Bite Mark. Is he still alive?
是的  臭得要命  活得挺好
Yeah, weasel breath, he's fine.
至少  一小时之前他还活着
He was, he was alive an hour ago at least.
好的  听着
Okay, listen.
-我需要你  -我该走了
- I need you... - Got to run.
等一下
Wait!
X光小队  X光小队
Delta-Xray... Delta-Xray.
X光小队
Delta-Xray.
该死
Damn it.
我真受够这样了
I can't take much more of this.
没关系  你现在安全了
It's okay. You're safe now.
你现在很安全  没人会伤害你
You're safe. No one's going to harm you.
再碰我一下我就杀了你
Touch me and I'll kill you.
甜心小宝贝  不要这样
Sweet child. That won't be necessary.
拜托  我们不会伤害你的
Please, the last thing we want is to harm you.
我的朋友们会来找我的
My friends are looking for me,
当他们找到我的时候就会杀了你
and when they find me they will kill you.
他们会把你们都杀了
They will kill all of you!
我知道了
I get it.
你不相信我
You don't trust me.
你怎么可能相信我
Why should you?
我知道你不会接受 但是我还是要说
I know you're not ready to hear this, but I'm going to say it anyway.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你是谁  你想要我做什么
Who are you? What do you want with me?
问得好
Fair questions.
如果我被强行绑过来我也会生气
I'd be angry too if I were brought here against my will.
对不起  我不想让你感到害怕
Please, I don't want you to be afraid.
我必须为过分热情的伙伴们的所作所为道歉
I... I must apologize about my overzealous companions.
他们都是好人
They're good men,
但是有时候我们不得不采取暴力手段
but sometimes we have to resort to less than civilized means.
我们生活在一个文明已经不复存在了的世界
We live in a less than civilized world.
这点你我都知晓
You know it. I know it.
所以  当我们遇到陌生人的时候
So... when we encounter strangers
整个家庭都要采取  必要的防范措施
the family needs to take... necessary precautions.
什么家庭
What family?
我们的家庭
Ours.
这里是我们的家
This is our home.
我有责任维持他们的幸福生活
And I am responsible for their well-being.
我是托拜亚斯?坎贝尔
I'm Tobias Campbell.
我猜你会觉得
I guess you can say
我在我们这个小家庭里扮演父亲的角色
I'm like a father to our little family.
但是在一个家庭里  我们互相照顾对方
But like a family, we take care of one another.
人人为我  我为人人
Everyone contributes. Everyone benefits.
这就是我们这三年来的生活写照
It's how we've survived the last three years.
这也是我们能继续生存下去的唯一方法
It's the only way we'll survive in the future.
你赞成吗
Don't you agree?
你一定饿了  请用吧
You must be hungry. Please eat.
我们还有很多可以分享
We have plenty to share.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
你会饿的
You will be.
在那之前  你不如跟着月影和暴风
Until then, why don't you go with Moonshade and Stormy.
女士们
Ladies,
麻烦费心给我们的新成员找些新衣服
be so kind as to find some fresh clothes for our newest member.
我可没说要加入你的...  家庭
I didn't say anything about joining your... family.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
不是我狂妄
I don't mean to be presumptuous.
只不过大家一看到
It's just that once people see
我们分享的友爱和慷慨
the love and bounty that we share
他们就不想离开了
they never want to leave us.
女士们
Ladies?
等等  所以这个叫洛基的家伙决斗输了吗
Wait, so this Rocky dude loses the fight?
是的  虽然看起来输了  实则是他赢了
Yeah. Yeah, but see in losing, he wins.
很有禅意
It's very zen.
我想看洛基跟僵尸决斗
I'd like to see Rocky fight a Z.
他输了就会被吃掉
If he loses, he gets eaten.
没事吧
Hey, is everything okay?
没事
Fine.
时间差不多了
It's about time.
怎么了  艾迪呢
What's wrong? Where's Addy?
失踪了
Missing.
她是被...
Is she...?
不是
No.
被活捉了
Taken alive.
什么
What?
被人抓走了
By humans.
谁
Who?
我们觉得你可能会知道
We thought you might know.
我  为什么我知道
Me? Why would I know?
你认识这些人吗
You recognize these guys?
不认识  为什么我会认识
No. Why would I?
左边这家伙是在泽西的两个车手之一
Creep on the left was one of those two bikers back in Jersey.
跟你朋友特拉维斯一起的
With your friend Travis.
我跟你说过  我不认识那家伙
I told you, I didn't know that guy.
我也不认识他们
And I don't know them either.
你现在就跟我说实话
You are gonna start telling me the truth right now
-不然我就在你身上打洞  -麦克
- or I am going to start blowing holes  - Mack.
-打到你说为止  -麦克
- in you until you do. - Mack.
听懂了没有
Do you understand me?
麦克  把枪拿开  把枪拿开
Mack. Put the gun away. Put the gun away.
你现在就把你知道的所有情况都告诉我们
You're gonna tell us everything you know about these guys right now.
不然我就毙了你
Or I'll shoot you.
我不能回去
I can't go back!
回哪里
Back where?
哪里  哪里  她在哪里  她在哪里
Where? Where? Where is she?! Where is she?!
该死
Shoot.
你看上去真漂亮
You look beautiful.
我就像一个末日的脱衣舞女  活见鬼
I look like a post-apocalyptic stripper. Jesus.
不如说是诱饵
More like bait.
快看看呐
Look at you.
妈妈会很高兴的
Mother will be so pleased.
晚饭很快就会好了
Supper will be ready soon.
摆好桌子
Set the table.
在妈妈旁边给我们的客人设个上座
And set a place of honor for our guest next to Mother.
麦克你在哪
Where are you Mack?
够了
Enough!
好了  卡桑德拉  别再废话
All right, Cassandra! No more bullshit.
赶紧告诉我们你知道的事
Tell us what you know. Now!
好吧  我认识他们
All right. I know them.
他们来自一群幸存者  叫大家庭什么的
They're part of a group of survivors. A family of sorts.
但其实更像是一群信徒
But more like a cult actually.
头领是一个叫托拜亚斯·坎贝尔的男人
Led by a man named Tobias Campbell.
我不能回去  我不会回去的
I can't go back there. I won't go back.
我们让你做什么你就做什么
You'll do whatever the hell we need you to do
把艾迪找回来
to get Addy back!
你们不知道  他们是危险人物
You don't know these people. They're dangerous.
我们也是
So are we.
那不一样
Not like they are.
托拜亚斯那群人比僵尸还可怕
Tobias and the others are worse than Zs.
我以为我逃离他们的魔掌了
I thought I'd gotten away from them,
但之后特拉维斯发现我和你们在一起
but then Travis spotted me with you.
你为什么要怕他们
Why are you so afraid of them?
你不懂
You don't get it.
你不能选择和谁一起生存
You don't pick who you survive with.
一开始我以为自己很幸运
At first I thought I was lucky.
他们起初和常人一样
They started out like everybody else.
托拜亚斯既聪明又强壮  他救了我们
Tobias was smart. He was strong. He saved us.
但黑色夏季来后  一切都变得如地狱般
But then Black Summer came, and everything went to hell.
有天在路上他就失去了理智
Somewhere along the way he lost his mind,
之后我们失去了灵魂  我不会回去
and... and we lost our souls. And I am not going back there!
他们会对艾迪怎样
What are they gonna do to Addy?
托拜亚斯会用奇怪的方式控制着家庭成员
Tobias has this weird control over people.
他会强迫你做些丧心病狂的事
He can make you do terrible things.
你的意思是  强奸她吗
What do you mean? Rape?
不  他会利用她做诱饵
No, he'll use her as bait.
诱饵吗  他们去抢劫吗
Bait? What, do they rob people?
不只是抢劫
Not just rob.
还杀人吗
Murder them?!
不  不是强奸或杀人
No! Not rape. Not murder.
他们不仅杀人  比这还要可怕
They don't just kill their victims. It's worse.
希望我们吃的不是狗肉
Well hope we are not eating dog.
天呐  不会吧
Oh God! Oh no! Oh God! Oh no! No!
晚饭好了
Supper's ready!
从前有一个农夫
There was this farmer.
他有只世上最聪明的猪  名叫阿诺德
Had the smartest pig in the world, Arnold.
这只猪能阅读会算数
This pig could read and do math.
阿诺德很有名
Arnold was famous.
有一天  农夫的朋友来访
And then one day, the farmer's friend, he comes over
他看到阿诺德用三只腿走动
and he sees Arnold tripping around on three legs.
他对农夫说  "可怜的阿诺德怎么了"
And he says to the farmer, "hey, what happened to poor Arnold?"
农夫说
And the farmer says
"像它这么聪明的猪  可不能一次就把它吃完"
"Smart pig like that, you don't eat him all at once."
怎么了啊  嫌故事太短吗
Oh, what? Too soon?
我们开始并不吃人
We didn't start out as cannibals.
吃人肉吗  这怎么可能
Cannibals? How is that even possible?
所有东西都染上了僵尸病毒
Everything's infected with the zombie virus.
如果你杀了吃了他们  你们也会感染
If you kill it and eat it, you get the live virus.
但是吃活肉的话...
But if you eat it alive...
我们只是一群想要求生的人
We were people just trying to survive.
托拜亚斯先从僵尸中救了我
Tobias saved me. First from the Zs.
救我与水深火热之中
Then from the worst of humanity.
他是个好人  之后他妻子病了
He was a good man. Then his wife got sick.
她没挺过去
She just couldn't take it anymore.
之后他就变成了另一个人
And he was never the same after that.
当黑色夏季来临
When Black Summer came
世界上所有人都在挨饿时
and everyone else in the world was starving,
他发誓会尽其所能保全大家
he swore he would do whatever it took to keep us alive.
他做到了
And he did.
我要回去找艾迪
I'm going back for Addy.
等等  麦克
Hang on, Mack.
加内特  别想拦住我
Garnett, do not try to stop me.
没人会拦你  我们都回去
Nobody's gonna try to stop you. We're all going back.
只是我们需要个计划
We just need a plan.
你们不懂  他们比僵尸还丧心病狂
You don't understand! These people are worse than Zs!
他们会把你们全杀了
They'll kill all of you!
她说得对  我们要为大局着想
Yeah, she's right. We need to look at the big picture.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你知道他们的据点吗
Do you know where they've taken her?
你可能觉得我们是禽兽  惨无人道
I know you think we're monsters. Inhuman.
我们一开始也这么想
We all did too at first.
但是饥饿最后总能改变一个人的想法
But hunger has a way of changing one's mind.
道德感会消失殆尽
Morality is stripped away.
只剩下想要生存下去的念头
And all that remains is survival.
我知道  你还需要适应一下
I know, this takes some getting used to.
也许这样会更合你的口味
Perhaps this will make it more palatable.
别这样  小花
Please, Little Flower.
你肯定饿坏了
You must be starving.
就吃一口补充点体力吧
Just a bite to keep your strength.
这可是我为你精心特制的
I made it special for you.
你这样惹得妈妈不高兴了
Now you've upset Mama.
我明白你一时还难以接受
I know this is a big adjustment.
但是身处乱世  不是吃人就是被吃
But in times like these, it's eat or be eaten.
请快快享用吧  妈妈爱你
So please. Mama likes you.
让她高兴点
Make her happy.
有鲜肉上门
Fresh meat.
你们俩把这块肉端回厨房
You two, get this meat back in the kitchen.
然后准备就位
Then get in position.
午安  朋友
Afternoon, friend.
如果你是来找女性伴游
If it's female companionship you're looking for,
那你就来对地方了
you've come to the right place.
事实上我是来找我朋友的
Actually I'm looking for my friend.
红发
Red head.
叫做艾迪
Goes by the name of Addy.
艾迪  艾迪  我不认识什么叫艾迪的人
Addy? Addy? Don't know anybody named Addy.
要是有我一定会记得
Sure would remember if we had one.
我们迷人的月影和暴风合你口味吗
Oh hey, how about the lovely Moonshade or Stormy?
今日特惠买一送一
We got a two for one special today.
听着  小混混
Listen, scumbag.
我知道她在你们手上
I know you got her.
十秒之后你把她送出来
You send her out here in the next ten seconds
否则小心你们这里遭殃
or a lot of bad shit is gonna start happening.
矮油  还挺难搞的嘛
Oooh, tough guy.
这只是脑袋一枪
That was a head shot.
我们对你朋友还算是客气的
We showed your friend some mercy.
对你就不一样了
I'm not gonna do the same for you.
下一枪会贯穿你的心脏
Next shot is going through your heart.
除非你想早早变成僵尸
So unless you want to be prematurely zombified,
否则还是把我朋友交出来
you get my friend out here.
赶紧的
Now.
你就不怕我先毙了你
Not if I blow you away first.
你不会这么做的  你会把艾迪还给我
You're not gonna do that. You're gonna get me Addy.
要是你动作够快  你还可以趁热吃了你朋友
And if you're quick about it, you can still eat your friend.
不必了
That won't be necessary.
加内特
Garnett!
还不到时候  还不到时候  别急
Not yet. Not yet. Come on.
显然你已经和我的阳光谈过了
Apparently you've been talking to my little Sunshine.
加内特  把我弄出来  这伙人疯了
Garnett, get me out of here. These people are insane.
再敢说一句我就吃了你的心脏
Say that again and I will eat your heart.
显然我们手里各有对方想要的人
Apparently we both have something the other wants.
不如我们做个交易
Perhaps we can make a deal.
把阳光还给我  你就能换回你的宝贝艾迪
Give me back my Sunshine, and you can have your precious Addy.
想得美  我不会和食人族谈判的
Nah, I'm not gonna negotiate with a cannibal.
你把艾迪交给我  我们就走
You're gonna give me Addy. We're gonna walk away.
你爱吃谁吃谁
And you can eat anybody you want.
你要知道谈判首要规则就是
You know the first rule of negotiation is
手握筹码最多的人赢
the person who wants it least wins.
要是你伤害她  我们就把你们一个个都干掉
If you harm her, we'll kill every one of you.
放马来
Kill away.
老实说几乎所有僵尸灾变的风浪我都挺过来了
Frankly I've had about all the zombie apocalypse I can take.
不过当然了  你和这姑娘会是第一个死的
But of course, you and the girl will be the first to die.
这样才对嘛
That's what I thought.
你知道谈判第二规则是什么吗
Do you know the second rule of negotiation?
什么
What?
手上有五十口径自动步枪的人赢
The guy with the 50 caliber machine gun wins.
听起来不怎么妙啊
That didn't sound good.
你究竟是想把我的阳光还给我
You gonna give me back my Sunshine?
还是想在这儿继续废话
Or do we continue this conversation in hell?
-别去  麦克  -不行  要死的话
- No, Mack. - No, no, if we're going to hell,
我也要带上这个王八蛋一起死
I'm going all the way and I'm taking this bastard with me.
-等一下  -你想干嘛
- Wait! - What do you want?!
我去
I'll go.
住手
Stop!
放了她  托拜亚斯
Let her go, Tobias.
你这是做什么
What are you doing?
做我一开始就该做的事
What I should have done in the first place.
放她走  我会回去的
Let her go, and I'll come back.
别这样  杀了他们  全杀了
Don't do it. Kill them. Kill them all.
-不行  -没关系  没事的
- No. - It's okay. It's okay.
快走
Come on.
没事了  没事了  宝贝
It's okay. It's okay, baby.
好了  我们走
It's okay. Come on. Let's go.
我的阳光
My Sunshine.
嘿  我们都要放弃你了呢
Hey, we about given up on you.
事实上我一个小时前就放弃你了
I actually gave up on you about an hour ago.
没想到再次看到你们这些蠢货我还挺高兴
Never thought I'd be happy to see your sad ass again.
我们马上离开这儿吧
Let's get out of here, guys. Now.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
走吧
Come on.
我们不...  不会扔下她不管的对吧
We're not... we're not leaving her there, are we?
艾迪  她撒谎了  差点害死你了
Addy. She lied to us. It almost got you killed.
我们不能这么做
We can't do that.
我们不能就这么扔下她
We can't just leave her there.
跟我一起上车
Come in the truck with me.
等确保你的安全之后我们在讨论这个
We'll talk about this when you're safe.
我不走
I am not going.
听着  他说得对
Look, he's right.
我们为了回去救你差点都死了
We almost all got killed going back for you.
对  她就是个恐怖的食人族  她活该
Yeah, she's a freakin' cannibal, and she got what she deserved.
她为了活命才迫不得已做那些事
She did what she had to do to survive.
所有人都会那么做
And you of all people would have done the same.
好了  艾迪说的没错
Come on, Addy is right!
我们不能把她扔在那里
We cannot leave her back there!
你们男人根本不明白
You men don't know what it's like.
什么情况  现在成了小妞们的事了吗
What is this, a chick thing now?
-是  -是
- Yes. - Yes.
那好吧  我也想帮她
All right, I want to help her too.
但是我们斗不过口径50的机关枪啊
But we're not gonna beat a 50 caliber machine gun.
还没到栅栏那儿我们就会被轰成碎片
It's gonna tear us to pieces before we get to the fence.
你枪法有多好
How good a shot are you?
相当好
Pretty good.
第1084个
One thousand eighty-four.
哦对了  还得再加上半个
Oh yeah, and a half.
好吧  我有个主意
Okay. I have an idea.
呼叫北极光  呼叫北极光
Calling Northern Light. Calling Northern Light.
请回话  北极光  听到了吗  完毕
Come in, Northern Light. Do you copy? Over.
请回话...  那个什么市民来着
Come in... Citizen whoever you are.
这里是三角洲X光小队
This is Delta-Xray-Delta.
你到底在哪儿  请回话  完毕
Where the hell are you? Come in. Over.
我在  我来了  北极光
I'm here. I'm here. Northern Light.
收到了  三角洲X光
Copy you Delta-Xray.
北极光  我们需要你的帮助  听到没
Northern Light, we need your help. Do you copy?
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
收到  女士  你要我做什么
Copy that, ma'am. What can I do?
我们需要音乐
We need music.
对不起  再说一遍
I'm sorry. Say again.
我好像听见你说你们需要音乐
It sounded like you said you needed music.
你没听错
That's a roger.
你能用调幅频率播放吗  完毕
Can you broadcast on the AM frequency? Over.
这里是美国国安局  女士
We're the NSA, ma'am.
我们掌控所有的频率
Master of all frequencies.
你们想听什么
What would you like to hear?
我们要用音乐吸引僵尸注意  声音要大
We need a diversion. Something loud.
要能够让僵尸变得疯狂
Something that'll make the Zs go crazy.
听到了  可以做到  女士
Copy that and can do, ma'am.
我应该是有这种东西
I think I have just the thing.
给我五分钟搜索一下
Give me five minutes and look for my broadcast
调幅广播低赫兹频段
on the low end of the AM dial.
多谢  伙计
Thanks, dude.
完毕
Over.
听到了吗  宝贝
Hear that boy?
他们需要我们
They need us.
有人真正需要我们
Somebody actually needs us.
你在这里  妈妈开心多了
Mama's so much happier when you're here.
鲜肉进了二号拖车
Got some fresh meat in trailer two
想要点异国情调
looking for something exotic.
到你了  阳光
You're on, Sunshine.
我想要的就是这种货色
That's what I'm talkin' about.
二十分钟  不能动粗
Twenty minutes and no rough stuff.
动粗都包括什么
Define rough stuff.
阳光会告诉你的
Sunshine will let you know.
哦  叫阳光啊
Oh. Sunshine.
你来这干什么
What are you doing?
我来做正确的事
The right thing.
按我说的做
Just follow my lead.
你们知道这么做会害死我们  是吧
You know this is gonna get us all killed, right?
至少死得有个性
At least we're going out with some style.
放大音量
Crank it up!
他们来了
Here they come.
想祈祷的话  现在正当时哦
If you got any prayers, now's the time.
-哦耶  宝贝  -天啊
- Oh yeah, baby! - Oh my God!
-爽  宝贝  -你的丁丁好大哦
- Yeah, baby! - Oh, you're so big!
-想要就给你  -好爽
- Take it! - Yes!
-且看爱情医生以茎制洞  -哦医生  快上马
- Love doctor in the house! - Oh, doctor!
就是这感觉倍儿爽  宝贝
Oh yeah! Yeah, baby!
倍儿爽  快骑上来  宝贝
Oh yeah! Ride it, baby!
哪个傻逼在放音乐
What fool is playing music?
太爽了
Yes!
听  那是信号
Listen. That's our signal.
继续  宝贝
Come on, baby!
伯恩特  去看看这是从哪传来的音乐
Bernt, see if you can tell where that music is coming from.
莫申特  准备好大口径机枪以防万一
Merchant, get on the 50 caliber just in case.
不  不  不要
No! No! Don't!
不  不
No! No!
进去
Now!
阳光
Sunshine.
我的名字是卡桑德拉
My name is Cassandra!
走吧  快
Let's go. Come on.
快去  快去
Let's go! Let's go!
阳光
Sunshine!
就现在了
It's now or never.
"我的城市"啊[60年代美国著名歌曲]
My kinda town.
如果有人问起  我们可从没接近过那座钟
If anybody asks, we were nowhere near that bell.
我总听说费城不好混  但这也太狠了
I always heard Philly was a tough town, but sheesh.
有意识的僵尸
Zombies with attitude.
希望我在费城附近的朋友们能听到这些
Hope my peeps down in the Philly area can hear this.
我想为他们的旅行播放一些蓝调
Thought I'd spin some blues to travel by.
也送给所有能听到我声音的人
And to anybody else out there within the sound of my voice.
希望美妙的吉他滑弦声
I hope some slide guitar
帮你扛过又一个死亡与毁灭的混乱的日子
gets you through another messed up day of death and destruction.
所有人  不管你是躲在山洞里
Everybody out there, whether you're hiding in a cave
还是疲于奔命
or running for your life,
请奋力生存下去
just keep doing what you got to do to stay alive.
因为最终  那会是我们战胜
Because in the end, that's the only way we're gonna win
僵尸大灾变的唯一方法
this Zombie Apocalypse thing.
殴他们  抽他们  捣碎他们  烧死他们
Bash 'em, slash 'em, bust 'em, and burn 'em.
不管付出什么代价  都要活下去
Whatever it takes. Just stay alive.
不问问题
No questions asked.